<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on sport-touring.eu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on sport-touring.eu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 09:47:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KDE Plasma 6: Don’t be fooled by the naysayers on the internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kde-plasma-6-dont-be-fooled-by-the-naysayers-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kde-plasma-6-dont-be-fooled-by-the-naysayers-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, KDE released their much anticipated next major release of the KDE desktop environment, version 6. The only distributions using it soon after were (obviously) KDE Neon, the KDE showcase / development platform, and the rolling release distributions like Arch and OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. The scheduled release distributions will only ship KDE6 in their next new release.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As it was released, obviously there were some teething problems despite a long and extensive beta test cycle and lots of bigfixing. Some of these were:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, 6 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 23:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, here we are, 6 months after installing OpenSUSE Tumbleweed and still no urge to change. The only change I am longing for is the update to KDE Plasma 6, which should be coming soon now that it has officially been released.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since there are basically no updates since my last post in &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/opensuse/opensuse-4-months-in/&#34;&gt;December&lt;/a&gt;, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to say. I did however made some changes. A couple of weeks ago, my GTX1080 decided to shit itself such that it triggers the short protection in the power supply so that&amp;rsquo;s out. Bit of a pain since everything is water cooled. I ended up replacing it with a Sapphire R9 390 Nitro which is an AMD based card. Raw speed is about half of that of the GTX1080, but at 50 euros it was cheap and being AMD means no more Nvidia issues on Linux as limited as they were for me. Main issue for me was that I had to manually recreate the initrd whenever a new driver version was released to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE: 4 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-4-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-4-months-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe it is time for a little update, even if there is not much to say. After 4 months of running OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, I can honestly say I have not had a single moment where I&amp;rsquo;d thought I should maybe look for another distribution because XYZ is getting too annoying.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course it does have some annoyances. Some are with me, like running systemd-boot while it is not officially ready for primetime yet. Others are with OpenSUSE or my setup, like sometimes an update will bork the system and I have to do a snapper rollback. Fortunately, OpenSUSE makes this a 2 minute job and so far, rolling back the update and installing it again is all that is needed to fix the system and the update.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Linux for desktop performance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/optimizing-linux-for-desktop-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/optimizing-linux-for-desktop-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My daily driver is currently Pop!_OS, which is a desktop Linux distribution. It&amp;rsquo;s a very nice distribution, really good with Nvidia hardware (which isn&amp;rsquo;t a given on Linux) and, to me, a Gnome look that is very close to what I want so my GUI changes are minimal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s less, and that is a more generic Linux problem, is that particularly the Linux kernel is optimized for server use and not desktop. It prioritizes throughput over latency, which is great for raw performance but less if you expect a smooth, fast GUI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving a Linux install to a new disk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/moving-a-linux-install-to-a-new-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/moving-a-linux-install-to-a-new-disk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I had to move my Linux install from one drive to another, as I was experiencing some issues with a WD SN550 nvme drive causing some short random freezes of the GUI with IO intensive tasks. Since I also have a Samsung nvme drive installed, I decided to see if the problem persists on the other drive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But. Having a fully configured and customized Linux install is a pain in the behind to redo. I did not want to clone, because I made a mistake during install the previous time and it installed in legacy MBR mode, so I wanted to do a proper install using UEFI mode. But preferably not having to re-do all the setup and customizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you know... (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://access.redhat.com/articles/2360841&#34;&gt;Convert2RHEL&lt;/a&gt; tool?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This also works for a LXC/LXD container?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will need to create a metafile.tar.gz with a few lines of information about the tarbal to do this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can also use an export from a Docker container to get the system?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And that you can also use an export from a WSL distribution for this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This means you can set up a WSL environment on your Windows box (see other posts here) just the way you want with all the tools you need, and you can export it to run it independently in a LXC/LXD container as a server?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Alpine Linux&lt;/a&gt;; extremely tiny; created from Docker image&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/AlmaLinux/almalinux-deploy&#34;&gt;AlmaLinux&lt;/a&gt;; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Arch Linux&lt;/a&gt;; created from virtual machine install&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wsldl-pg/CentWSL&#34;&gt;CentOS 7&lt;/a&gt;; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Deepin Linux&lt;/a&gt;; created from virtual machine install&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Fedora&lt;/a&gt;; created from virtual machine installation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/gentoo-on-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Gentoo&lt;/a&gt;; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kali Linux; Microsoft Store&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linux.oracle.com/switch/centos/&#34;&gt;Oracle Linux&lt;/a&gt;; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;RedHat Enterprise Linux&lt;/a&gt;; created from virtual machine installation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rocky-linux/rocky-tools/tree/main/migrate2rocky&#34;&gt;Rocky Linux&lt;/a&gt;; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ubuntu; Microsoft Store&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.crashdot.com/posts/wsl/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/&#34;&gt;Slackware&lt;/a&gt;; created from Docker image&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own. It&amp;rsquo;s not that difficult and really there is no reason why you should not have the Linux distribution of your choice available under WSL2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt; WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
