<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wsl on sport-touring.eu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/wsl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wsl on sport-touring.eu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/wsl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Did you know... (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available? There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora? You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the Convert2RHEL tool? This also works for a LXC/LXD container? You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container? You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&#xA;Alpine Linux; extremely tiny; created from Docker image AlmaLinux; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool Arch Linux; created from virtual machine install CentOS 7; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7 CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install Deepin Linux; created from virtual machine install Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store Fedora; created from virtual machine installation Gentoo; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge Kali Linux; Microsoft Store Oracle Linux; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle RedHat Enterprise Linux; created from virtual machine installation Rocky Linux; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool Ubuntu; Microsoft Store Slackware; created from Docker image As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&#xA;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
