<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Containers on sport-touring.eu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Containers on sport-touring.eu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 09:47:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>As short as possible: application containers, system containers, virtualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, there is a bit of confusion as to what the difference is between application containers (Docker, Podman, K8S, OpenShift), system containers (LXC/LXD) and virtualization (KVM, Vmware, Hyper-V, Xen) and when you should use them. I will try to explain the differences as short as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;application-containers&#34;&gt;Application containers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Application containers are created with the most minimal environment to run a specific application. This includes the OS and all dependencies for that application. Every tool or program normally present in the OS that is not needed to run the application is typically left out so that the container image is a small as possible and performs as fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you know... (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://access.redhat.com/articles/2360841&#34;&gt;Convert2RHEL&lt;/a&gt; tool?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This also works for a LXC/LXD container?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You will need to create a metafile.tar.gz with a few lines of information about the tarbal to do this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can also use an export from a Docker container to get the system?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;And that you can also use an export from a WSL distribution for this?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This means you can set up a WSL environment on your Windows box (see other posts here) just the way you want with all the tools you need, and you can export it to run it independently in a LXC/LXD container as a server?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
