<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer on sport-touring.eu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer on sport-touring.eu</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:34:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>KDE Plasma 6: Don’t be fooled by the naysayers on the internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kde-plasma-6-dont-be-fooled-by-the-naysayers-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 21:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/kde-plasma-6-dont-be-fooled-by-the-naysayers-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>About a month ago, KDE released their much anticipated next major release of the KDE desktop environment, version 6. The only distributions using it soon after were (obviously) KDE Neon, the KDE showcase / development platform, and the rolling release distributions like Arch and OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. The scheduled release distributions will only ship KDE6 in their next new release.&#xA;As it was released, obviously there were some teething problems despite a long and extensive beta test cycle and lots of bigfixing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, 6 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 23:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-tumbleweed-6-months-in/</guid>
      <description>Well, here we are, 6 months after installing OpenSUSE Tumbleweed and still no urge to change. The only change I am longing for is the update to KDE Plasma 6, which should be coming soon now that it has officially been released.&#xA;Since there are basically no updates since my last post in December, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much to say. I did however made some changes. A couple of weeks ago, my GTX1080 decided to shit itself such that it triggers the short protection in the power supply so that&amp;rsquo;s out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSUSE: 4 months in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-4-months-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 18:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/opensuse-4-months-in/</guid>
      <description>Maybe it is time for a little update, even if there is not much to say. After 4 months of running OpenSUSE Tumbleweed, I can honestly say I have not had a single moment where I&amp;rsquo;d thought I should maybe look for another distribution because XYZ is getting too annoying.&#xA;Of course it does have some annoyances. Some are with me, like running systemd-boot while it is not officially ready for primetime yet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interesting (or: first tiling windows manager experience)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/nteresting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/nteresting/</guid>
      <description>The other night, I was playing around watching YouTube videos and was watching this one video from Brodie Robertson on how he was now using Hyprland as his daily driver. Usually, I just zone out to other tasks when the topic gets to a tiling window manager, as it is not for me: I have a ultrawide screen on my desktop, with a 3440x1440 resolution and trust me, you do not want to run console fullscreen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No more Windows. FreeBSD instead.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2023-10-10-no-more-windows-freebsd-instead/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2023-10-10-no-more-windows-freebsd-instead/</guid>
      <description>No, I did not stop running OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. That&amp;rsquo;s still my daily driver. I did however wipe my Windows drive and installed FreeBSD instead. I have used FreeBSD quite a lot way back when, and since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t actually booted into Windows for months, I just decided to install FreeBSD on that drive so I could play with it again after I saw KDE is actively supporting FreeBSD for the desktop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The end to distro-hopping?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/the-end-to-distro-hopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 21:33:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/the-end-to-distro-hopping/</guid>
      <description>Since I have moved to running Linux basically full time, I have ran Pop!OS, Fedora, Nobara, back to Fedora KDE Spin and now OpenSUSE Tumbleweed. All of them are good distributions and none have any real deal-breakers for me not to want to use them.&#xA;The fact that I really, really like Tumbleweed was not a given. Quite the contrary. OpenSUSE does it&amp;rsquo;s own thing, so it is a bit of a learning curve if you are used to Debian-based or RedHat-based distributions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running redundant AdGuard@Home DNS servers on Synology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/running-redundant-adguardhome-dns-servers-on-synology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 12:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/running-redundant-adguardhome-dns-servers-on-synology/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick post on how to run multiple instances of AdGuard@Home on a single Synology host using Docker.&#xA;Problem: you cannot easily, using Docker, run multiple instances of the same program - or different program - while listening on the same port.&#xA;Solution: do not use host or bridge networking, but put the container on the same network as the host using macvlan.&#xA;To achieve this, we need to do the following:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Linux for desktop performance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/optimizing-linux-for-desktop-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 19:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/optimizing-linux-for-desktop-performance/</guid>
      <description>My daily driver is currently Pop!_OS, which is a desktop Linux distribution. It&amp;rsquo;s a very nice distribution, really good with Nvidia hardware (which isn&amp;rsquo;t a given on Linux) and, to me, a Gnome look that is very close to what I want so my GUI changes are minimal.&#xA;What&amp;rsquo;s less, and that is a more generic Linux problem, is that particularly the Linux kernel is optimized for server use and not desktop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving a Linux install to a new disk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/moving-a-linux-install-to-a-new-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 19:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/moving-a-linux-install-to-a-new-disk/</guid>
      <description>Recently I had to move my Linux install from one drive to another, as I was experiencing some issues with a WD SN550 nvme drive causing some short random freezes of the GUI with IO intensive tasks. Since I also have a Samsung nvme drive installed, I decided to see if the problem persists on the other drive.&#xA;But. Having a fully configured and customized Linux install is a pain in the behind to redo.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring your network or homelab using Zabbix and Grafana</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/monitoring-your-network-or-homelab-using-zabbix-and-grafana/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time, I have been monitoring my network and homelab using Observium. This worked and does work very well. Observium is very good at what it does. However, there are a couple of things that do not work so well for me using Observium:&#xA;Observium does not let me add applications to monitor very easily or at all Observium is limited to what can be offered through SNMP Observium is not open source and as such it cannot be modified or changed to your needs Observium is not an application I have come across in my professional life, so knowing how it works does not help me professionally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>As short as possible: application containers, system containers, virtualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/application-containers-system-containers-virtualization/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, there is a bit of confusion as to what the difference is between application containers (Docker, Podman, K8S, OpenShift), system containers (LXC/LXD) and virtualization (KVM, Vmware, Hyper-V, Xen) and when you should use them. I will try to explain the differences as short as possible.&#xA;Application containers Application containers are created with the most minimal environment to run a specific application. This includes the OS and all dependencies for that application.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Did you know... (or, RHEL on LXC/LXD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 09:40:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/rhel-on-lxc-lxd/</guid>
      <description>There are no RedHat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) LXC/LXD container images publicly available? There are LXC/LXD container images available for CentOS and Fedora? You can convert a CentOS install to RHEL using the Convert2RHEL tool? This also works for a LXC/LXD container? You will need to do this if you want to run RHEL on Proxmox in a LXC container? You can create a tarbal of a running system to import into a vanilla LXC/LXD installation?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tested distributions under WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 22:16:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/tested-distributions-under-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>The following distributions I have installed/created, tested and used under WSL2 and Windows 10.&#xA;Alpine Linux; extremely tiny; created from Docker image AlmaLinux; migrated from CentOS using AlmaLinux migration tool Arch Linux; created from virtual machine install CentOS 7; created from rootfs image, then upgraded to latest version CentOS 8; Upgraded from CentOS7 CentOS Stream; upgraded from from CentOS8 install Deepin Linux; created from virtual machine install Debian 10 (Buster); Microsoft Store Debian Testing (Bullseye); upgraded from official Debian 10 release Devuan; migrated from Debian as installed from the Microsoft Store Fedora; created from virtual machine installation Gentoo; compiled from source using Stage3 tarball/rootfs iamge Kali Linux; Microsoft Store Oracle Linux; migrated from CentOS instance using CentOS migration tool from Oracle RedHat Enterprise Linux; created from virtual machine installation Rocky Linux; migrated from CentOS using RockyLinux migration tool Ubuntu; Microsoft Store Slackware; created from Docker image As you can see, if you can find your favorite distribution in the Microsoft Store, great, if not or if its only available as a paid distribution, just bake your own.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Any Linux distribution on Windows 10 with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/any-linux-distribution-on-windows-10-with-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a Linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a lightweight hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 is required.&#xA;An explanation on how to enable WSL2 support can be found on the page detailing how to create a Gentoo instance on WSL2.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo on Windows with WSL2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 15:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/gentoo-on-wsl/</guid>
      <description>Introduction WSL 2 on Windows 10 introduced the ability to run a native linux kernel on your computer while using Windows 10 as your main operating system. Instead of emulating a linux kernel, like WSL 1 does, WSL 2 uses a hypervisor to run linux in parallel with Windows.&#xA;To be able to run WSL 2 on Windows 10, installation of Windows 10 feature update 2004 or newer is required.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
